<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Art Makes Us</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Art Makes Us</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 14:05:49 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Interface</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/interface/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 14:05:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/interface/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Lasalle College of the Arts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Category&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Theater&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About This Project&lt;/strong&gt;
nterface is a multi-disciplinary collaborative project that explores the symbiosis between interactive media and dance performance. Based on contextual research, custom-made technology is used to translate body movement and site-specific spaces into audio-visual expressions. In each performance installation by Level 2 BA(Hons) dance students, interactive technology synergises with dance choreography as an expressive tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dancers&lt;/em&gt; – Anita Anton, Eva Tey, Samantha Lau, Lim Ming Zhi, Zhou Yiru&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Media artists&lt;/em&gt; – Mui Rui YI, Benjamin Low, Mithru Vigneshwara, Adam Aw, Zac Ong&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Mentor&lt;/em&gt; – Melissa Quek and Andreas Schlegel&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abstraction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/abstraction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 13:59:58 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/abstraction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exhibition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Lasalle College of the Arts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Category&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Theater&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About This Project&lt;/strong&gt;
Abstraction is a performance installation inspired by avant garde British theatre group Complicite’s A Disappearing Number. Key themes explored include the beauty of mathematics, a cultural collision of East and West, and the interconnectedness of human relationships. Conceptualised as visual pageantry and drawing references from leading contemporary artists like Robert Wilson and Robert Lepage, this work seeks to explore new perspectives in medium accessible to audiences in the 21st Century.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Merging real-time technology with live performance, this innovation in theatre questions the line between theatrical conventions and new media art. Abstraction aims to leave a deep impression in the audience’s mind as to how seemingly disparate themes of love and mathematics can be beautifully intertwined into a story. Abstraction is a collaboration by students from Theatre+Performance, Acting and Interactive Art at LASALLE College of the Arts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cast&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Aninda&lt;/em&gt; – Andrew Sutherland&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Ruth&lt;/em&gt; – Chng XIn Xuan&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Al&lt;/em&gt; – Benedict Hew&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Ramanujan&lt;/em&gt; – Ali Anwar&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Hardy&lt;/em&gt; – Kyle Gannon&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Jenaki&lt;/em&gt; – Farez Najid&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Ramanujan’s Mother&lt;/em&gt; – Rytasha Rathod&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Surita&lt;/em&gt; – Frances Lee&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Lecture student / Passenger&lt;/em&gt; – Dominque De Marco&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Lecture student / Passenger&lt;/em&gt; – Morweena Maclean&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Barbara&lt;/em&gt; – chanel chan&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Harvard Professor&lt;/em&gt; – Shana Yap&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Fellow#1&lt;/em&gt; – Lian Sutton&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Fellow#2&lt;/em&gt; – Axel Renevey&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Project Leaders&lt;/em&gt; – Cherilyn Woo &amp;amp; Mithru Vigneshwara&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Assistant project Leaders&lt;/em&gt; – Khairul Kamsani&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Directors&lt;/em&gt; – Cherilyn Woo, Khairul Kamsani, Rachael Nonis, Fairuz Atiqah&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Set Designer&lt;/em&gt; – Mithru Vigneshwara&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Visual Composers&lt;/em&gt; – Jacky Boen, Adam Aw &amp;amp; Mui Rui Yi&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Interaction Designer / Developer&lt;/em&gt; – Zac Ong&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Sound Designer&lt;/em&gt; – Khairul Kamsani, Benjamin Low, Adam Aw&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Stage Manager&lt;/em&gt; – Josiah Yoong&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Sound Engineer&lt;/em&gt; – Sage Tan&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Costume and props Co-ordinator&lt;/em&gt; – Fairuz Atiqah&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Projection engineer&lt;/em&gt; – Kailash&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Front of House Manager&lt;/em&gt; – Rachael Nonis&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COCK</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/cock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 13:53:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/cock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exhibition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Singapore Drama Centre, Black Box&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Category&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Theater&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About This Project&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;COCK&lt;/em&gt; by Mike Bartlett is a theatre production presented by the Buds Theatre Company and directed by Rayann Condy. It was shown at Singapore Drama Centre, Black Box, on 10 -12 MAY 2012.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ArtMakesUs created the projection mapping visual effects for certain scene transitions in the play. The visual concept is based on the idea that the set reflects the state of mind of the protagonist – John, with waves signifying the passing of time or sexual activity in the style of a wire frame. The visual effects were created using an open source software called Processing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Director&lt;/em&gt; – Rayann Condy&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Producer&lt;/em&gt; – Claire Devine&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Visual Artists&lt;/em&gt; – Jacky Boen, Mithru Vigneshwara, Mui RuiYi and Zac Ong.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Lighting Design&lt;/em&gt; – Shaiful Islam&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Sound Design&lt;/em&gt; – Jean Low&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Actors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;John&lt;/em&gt; – Walter Hanna&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Men&lt;/em&gt; – Koey Foo&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Women&lt;/em&gt; – Rebecca Lee&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Father&lt;/em&gt; – Ray Condy&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synesthete&#39;s Music Box</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/synesthete/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 13:39:59 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/synesthete/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exhibition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Penang mini makerfaire 2014, Sg Festival 2014&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Category&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Art&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About This Project&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The Synaesthete’s Music Box&lt;/em&gt; is a sound machine inspired by the idea of synesthesia. A synesthete is someone who perceives secondary sensations involuntarily through another sensory stimulation. For example, a synesthete will “see” explosions of colour in his mind when listening to loud music, or ‘hear’ sounds in his head when viewing a painting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This music box converts colours into sound. A webcam sees the colours on the turntable. A custom program then interprets the image in real time to trigger sounds. Play around with different colour arrangements to create your own unique sounds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circle Of Light</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/circleoflight/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 13:27:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/circleoflight/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exhibition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Penang mini maker faire 2014, SG Festival 2014&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
May 01, 2014&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Category&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Art&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About This Project&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Circle of Light&lt;/em&gt; is photography booth where users can take their own photos while selecting a light painted image and/or text as a photo background and share them on their favourite social networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The setup includes a LPD8806 64-LED strip hooked onto a wooden stick which is rotated by a servo motor controlled by an Arduino. A computer acts as a web app server for users to send images / text from their own machines (mobile phones or PCs). The server receives the assets sent by the user, sends the data to the Arduino for display and triggers the camera capture.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>contact</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 12:55:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The River</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/theriver/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2015 14:23:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/theriver/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exhibition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
iLight Festival 2012, Art Science Museum&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
July 01, 2012&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Category&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Art&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About This Project&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The River&lt;/em&gt; is a light sculpture inspired by the beauty and history of the Singapore River. It consists of several laser cut acrylic sheets illuminated by 72 LEDs, taking on the shape of the Singapore River as seen from a map. The light animation is programmed based on an analysis of sound samples recorded along the Singapore River.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ArtMakesUs made this sculpture during their second year as Interactive Art students from LASALLE College of the Arts, under the supervision of their lecturer Andreas Schlegel. It was exhibited at i Light Marina Bay 2012, a sustainable light festival held at Marina Bay, Singapore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The River is created in celebration of Asia’s only sustainable light festival and also in accordance with the theme of “Light Meets Asia”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Focusing on the idea of “Light as Life”, the concept of the artwork is based on the idea that the Singapore River is a microcosm of Singapore, transforming with Singapore over the years and reflective of its identity today. The light animation based on sound samples collected over a day symbolises the daily activities along the river.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>